all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh... *
-*哦...*
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
所有：海绵宝宝！
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
* *
**
- Ooh, take a look at this,
Gare Bear.
- 哦，看看这个，
盖尔熊.
Found a slime ball
in your shoe?
发现一个粘液球
在你的鞋子里？
Even purebred snails
can fall victim
即使是纯种蜗牛
可能成为受害者
to the scourge of slime balls.
对付粘液球的祸害。
[Gary hacking,
SpongeBob groans]
[加里黑客，
海绵宝宝呻吟]
You really got some air
on that one.
你确实有一些空气
在那一个上。
- Meow.
- 喵。
- I know that meow.
- 我知道那个喵。
That says "I'm hungry."
那句话是“我饿了”。
Lucky for you,
I speak fluent snail.
你很幸运，
我能说流利的蜗牛语。
- Meow!
- 喵！
- Meow-meow!
- 喵喵！
- Oh, of course!
- 哦，当然！
You wanna go for a walk?
你想去散步吗？
Gary, you really need to work
on your pronunciation.
加里，你真的需要工作
关于你的发音。
Okay, no walkies.
好吧，没有步话机。
- Oh, if only you could talk
like a person.
- 哦，如果你能说话就好了
像一个人。
Ooh!
哦！
"The chatterbox
translation collar?
“话匣子
翻译领？
Know what your best friend
is saying!"
知道你最好的朋友是什么
正在说！”
A snail translator!
蜗牛翻译器！
That's a great idea, Gary.
这是个好主意，加里。
- Chatterbox order line.
- 话匣子订单行。
- Hello, yes,
could you please send me
- 你好，是的，
你能发给我吗
one chatterbox snail collar?
一个话匣子蜗牛项圈？
- Do you want regular, express,
- 您想要普通的、特快的、
or our fastest delivery option,
time warp?
或我们最快的交付选项，
时间扭曲？
- Ooh, time warp, please!
- 哦，时间扭曲，拜托！
- Very well, your package
was delivered last Thursday.
- 很好，你的包裹
已于上周四交付。
- Oh, I wonder
where this came from.
- 哦，我想知道
这是从哪里来的。
Oh, here we go.
哦，我们开始吧。
Okay, Gary, speak to me.
好吧，加里，跟我说话。
- Check, check.
- 检查，检查。
- One, two.
- 一，二。
Ah, that's more like it.
啊，这更像是这样。
Hello, there, Papa Bob.
你好，鲍勃爸爸。
- Papa Bob.
- 鲍勃爸爸。
Oh!
Oh, Gary,
哦！
哦，加里，
now you can express
your innermost thoughts
现在你可以表达
你内心深处的想法
in language I can understand.
用我能理解的语言。
I have so many questions.
我有很多问题。
- Lay 'em on me, Papa Bob.
- 把它们放在我身上，鲍勃爸爸。
- Mostly I dream
I'm flying above it all...
- 主要是我在做梦
我飞翔在这一切之上...
- Aww, that's sweet.
- 哇，太甜了。
- While I breathe fiery
destruction
- 当我呼吸着火热的时候
破坏
upon my enemies.
临到我的敌人身上。
Hey, if you're gonna dream,
嘿，如果你要梦想，
dream big, right?
梦想很大，对吗？
Let's move on
让我们继续前进
to question two,
shall we?
提出问题二，
我们可以吗？
What are your long
你的长是多少
- To finish
restoring my hotrod.
- 完成
恢复我的热棒。
- Yeah,
you need to get on that.
- 是的，
你需要继续下去。
But what I really
want to know is,
但我真正
想知道的是，
how do I look
in these pants?
我看起来怎么样
在这条裤子里？
- They really bring out
- 他们真的带出来了
the sharp corners
of your buttocks.
尖角
你的臀部。
- Oh, Gary, you flatterer.
- 哦，加里，你这个马屁精。
Come on, Gare, let's show
Patrick your new voice.
来吧，Gare，让我们展示一下
帕特里克，你的新声音。
Oh, Patrick, I have got
a surprise for you!
哦，帕特里克，我有
给你一个惊喜！
Say hello to Gary.
向加里问好。
- Hello, Gary.
- 你好，加里。
- Hello, stinky man.
- 你好，臭男人。
Hmm.
唔。
Phew!
唷！
Ooh, you're right, Gary,
I am ripe!
哦，你是对的，加里，
我成熟了！
Ah, much better.
啊，好多了。
- Delightfully disgusting.
- 令人愉快的恶心。
- Thank you, my good man.
- 谢谢你，我的好人。
- Thanks for the old
tooth scrubbing!
- 谢谢老
刷牙！
Bye!
- Sandy!
再见！
- 桑迪！
Gary has a new
translating collar.
加里有一个新的
翻译领。
- Hello, hairy astronaut lady.
- 你好，毛茸茸的宇航员女士。
- You know, same shell,
different day.
- 你知道，同样的外壳，
不同的一天。
- Aww, that ain't nothing.
- 哇哦，那没什么。
I invented a nut translator
ages ago.
我发明了坚果翻译器
很久以前。
- The pistachios
are all out to get me.
- 开心果
都想抓我。
You can't trust 'em.
你不能相信他们。
They're working
for the peanut mafia!
他们正在工作
为了花生黑手党！
Walnuts are extra nutty.
核桃有额外的坚果味。
- Om.
- 唵。
- In order to achieve
complete brainfulness,
- 为了实现
完全的头脑，
one must clear one's mind
of all distractions.
必须清醒头脑
排除一切干扰。
Distractions are only
in your mind.
干扰只是
在你的脑海里。
- You are the center
of the universe.
- 你是中心
宇宙的。
- Center of the universe.
- 宇宙中心。
[doorbell continues ringing,
Squidward continues grumbling]
[门铃继续响，
章鱼哥继续抱怨]
- Will you answer the door
already?
- 你会开门吗
已经？
- I think your doorbell's
broken, Squidward.
- 我想你的门铃是
破碎了，章鱼哥。
- I thought you might want to
chat with your neighbor.
- 我以为你可能想要
和你的邻居聊天。
- Why would I want to
talk to you?
- 为什么我想要
跟你说话吗？
- Oh, not to me.
To Gary.
- 哦，对我来说不是。
给加里.
- Oh, good grief.
SpongeBob, Gary can't talk.
- 哦，真可惜。
海绵宝宝、加里不会说话。
He's a snail!
他是一只蜗牛！
- Greetings and salutations,
grouchy man.
- 问候和问候，
脾气暴躁的人。
- I bought Gary the new pet
translator collar.
- 我给加里买了新宠物
翻译领。
- Why would you
want to talk to him?
- 你为什么要
想和他说话吗？
- Who wouldn't want to
talk to their pet?
- 谁不想
和他们的宠物说话？
- I was talking to Gary.
- 我正在和加里说话。
- Oh.
Those walls!
- 哦。
那些墙！
That carpet.
那块地毯。
- Turns out Gary
has a very sophisticated
- 事实证明加里
有一个非常复杂的
sense of design.
设计感。
Well, maybe I'll give him
the guided tour.
好吧，也许我会给他
导游。
- Hey, wait up!
- 嘿，等等！
- And up here, you'll find
my true masterworks,
- 在这里，你会发现
我真正的杰作，
Hidden away from the eyes
of the undeserving public.
隐藏在远离视线的地方
不值得的公众。
- Ah, the naive
cephalopod style.
- 啊，天真
头足类动物风格。
Not very sophisticated.
不是很复杂。
See here.
请参阅此处。
- Ugh!
Tacky.
- 呃！
俗气。
- Hold on now!
- 坚持住！
- Don't worry, Squidward,
I'm taking notes for you.
- 别担心，章鱼哥
我正在为你做笔记。
- Feel the plainfulness
flow through you.
- 感受平淡
流过你。
What's wrong with it?
有什么问题吗？
- Nothing, I'm sure.
- 没什么，我确定。
Apparently, no brain required.
显然，不需要大脑。
Come, Papa Bob.
来吧，鲍勃爸爸。
Let's get out of here
我们离开这里吧
before this bad taste
rubs off on us.
在这糟糕的味道之前
影响我们。
- Don't be sad, Squidward,
we'll be back soon.
- 别伤心，章鱼哥，
我们很快就会回来。
- Until next time,
- 直到下次，
remember to free yourself
记得释放自己
from all distraction.
远离一切干扰。
- Oh, I will.
- 哦，我会的。
Night, Gare Bear.
晚上，盖尔熊。
- Good night, Papa Bob.
- 晚安，鲍勃爸爸。
- Good night.
- 晚安。
- Ah, let's see if SpongeBob
- 啊，让我们看看海绵宝宝是否
still wants you to talk
after tonight.
还是想让你说话
今晚之后。
Stupid rake!
愚蠢的耙子！
Oh, Papa Bob.
哦，鲍勃爸爸。
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
Oh, Papa Bob.
哦，鲍勃爸爸。
- I'm thirsty.
- 我渴了。
At this hour?
这个时候？
All right, I'll get you
some water.
好吧，我来接你
一些水。
- Here you go, buddy,
- 给你，伙计，
one water.
一水。
- I want to go to the park.
- 我想去公园。
Oh, sure.
No problem, Gary.
哦，当然。
没问题，加里。
Well, that was fun.
嗯，那很有趣。
- My bed is too lumpy.
- 我的床太凹凸不平了。
- All right, then.
- 好吧，那么。
Here, Gary, take my bed, hmm?
在这里，加里，占据我的床，嗯？
- Papa Bob, it's hot in here.
- 鲍勃爸爸，这里很热。
- Still too stuffy.
- 还是太闷了。
- Still too--
——还是——
How's that, Gary?
怎么样，加里？
- The view is so much nicer
a block away.
- 景色好多了
一个街区远。
- Okay, okay.
- 好吧，好吧。
This should get things rolling.
这应该能让事情顺利进行。
- Keep going.
- 继续前进。
Just a little more.
再多一点。
Perfect.
完美的。
You're right, Gary.
你是对的，加里。
The view is nicer over here.
这里的景色更好。
Gary?
Gary!
加里？
加里！
[wheels screech,
houses clatter]
[车轮吱吱作响，
房屋嘎嘎作响]
Whoa!
哇！
Oh-whoa-oh! Oh, god!
Oh, god!
哦-哇-哦！哦，天啊！
哦，天啊！
Whew!
哇！
Aww, that was close, huh, Gary?
哇哦，很接近了，是吧，加里？
Oops.
哎呀。
- Aww, now where are
we gonna sleep?
- 哇，现在在哪里
我们要睡觉吗？
You could always live
你可以永远活下去
in a hole,
like that idiot sea star.
在一个洞里，
就像那个白痴海星一样。
- My house!
- 我的房子！
Oh, Squidward,
we're neighbors again.
哦，章鱼哥，
我们又是邻居了。
- Get off of...
- 下车...
- Uh, I didn't catch that,
Squidward, what'd you say?
- 呃，我没听清，
章鱼哥，你说什么？
- I said, "Get off of"...
- 我说，“滚开”...
- Hey!
- 嘿！
Come back with my worm!
带着我的虫子回来吧！
- Aww, looks like Squidward
- 哇哦，看起来像章鱼哥
wants a pet of his own
to talk to.
想要一只自己的宠物
交谈。
Meow.
喵。